# **MOHAMMAD UVAIZ**

Web Developer

+91-9636245087 mohammeduvaiz0786@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mohammad-uvaiz-57353620b/ Jaipur

#### Summary

As a web developer with a moderate level of backend knowledge, particularly in Node.js. Currently enrolled as a computer science student at Arya College, Jaipur, I am passionate about working on multiple projects that challenge my abilities and push the boundaries of my problem-solving skills. I'm on the lookout for an opportunity that not only allows me to contribute my web development expertise but also offers an environment where I can work collaboratively and learn continuously. My innate curiosity drives me to seek new challenges and knowledge in the ever-evolving world of web development, making me a motivated and adaptable candidate ready to make a positive impact.

### Skills

Soft Skills: Problem Solving ,Time management, Communication skills, Leadership

Technical skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node Js, Express Js, MongoDb, Tailwind CSS, Core Java, Data Structures

### Experience

# Talentship global advisory forum

Remote

# Backend Developer Intern

10/2023 - Present

- Successfully collaborated in a cross-functional team of developers, designers, and testers
- · Rapidly acquired and applied knowledge of new Node.js libraries and frameworks

Insight Gro Remote

Frontend Developer 11/2022 - 01/2023

- · Developed responsive and user-friendly web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- · Proactively learned about the new JavaScript library React during the internship and successfully applied it to enhance the interactivity

#### Education

ARYA Institute of Engineering & Technology B.Tech in Computer Science	Jaipur, Rajasthan 08/2020 - Present
Dhruva Bal NIketan , School	Jaipur, Rajasthan
Senior Secondary (12th)	05/2019 - 03/2020
Dhruva Bal Niketan , School	Jaipur, Rajasthan
Secondary (10th)	05/2017 - 03/2018

## Courses & Certificates

Java with DSA - PW Skills

Node JS Master the fundamentals - Scaler Academy

Frontend Web Development - Udemy

### **Projects**

#### NewsHub

### Social Connect

### Short URL

- NewsHub is a dynamic news application that leverages the NewsAPI to provide real-time access to news articles from diverse sources
- Gained hands-on experience in API integration, data fetching, and dynamic content
- Rendering Implemented responsive design for optimal viewing on both desktop and mobile devices
- Designed and developed a social media website using Node.js, featuring robust user authentication, post creation
- Gained learning of handling user authentication using external middlewares like passport js
- a valuable learning experience that honed my skills in full-stack web development
- Designed and developed a URL Shortener web application using Node.js, with robust user authentication and URL shortening features.
- Gained learning of JWT for Authentication and Server Side Rendering and lot more .
- You can explore the live demo <u>here</u> and find the source code on GitHub.

# Interests & Hobbies

## Singing

### I am fond of Singing and loves to sing, it's a way for me to express myself, connect with others

## Watching Movies

Along with my work, I prefer to watch movies on the weekends for entertainment purposes